Hogenauer, Clare; Papers apap349
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Clare Hogenauer Papers
1999-2006, Undated
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Hogenauer, Clare
apap349
0.93 cubic ft.
The Clare Hogenauer Papers document her activism against the death penalty.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Clare Hogenauer donated her papers to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections in 2006.
Biographical Sketch
Clare Hogenauer is a retired New York City attorney who has been a death penalty opponent for decades. She has attended death penalty trials, lobbied government, spoken to school groups about capital punishment, and testified before legislative bodies during state death penalty hearings, including ones in Massachusetts, Connecticut and New Jersey.
Scope and Contents
The Clare Hogenauer Papers document her activism and efforts to try to abolish capital punishment. The majority of the collection consists of VHS tapes recording death penalty abolitionist events and speakers, especially those from Journey of Hope. There also are videos recording news of executions and a small number of paper records, including Hogenauer's testimony in New Jersey against the death penalty.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized chronologically. There are no series.
Capital punishment--Political aspects--United States; Capital punishment--Social aspects--United States; Capital punishment--United States--Cases; VHS (TM); Hogenauer, Clare; Journey of Hope...From Violence to Healing (death penalty abolitionist organization)
- Wrongly Convicted: How the Innocent are Sent to Death Row. A Definitive Symposium, 1999 September 16 (Video-tape 1)
- Stephen LaValle Resentencing, Riverhead, NY, 2004 August (Video-tape 2)
- 44th Street Hearing; Michael Ross Execution Vigil; CT Hearings, 2005 January 29; 2005 January 31 (Video-tape 3)
- Michael Ross' Execution Vigil, Somers, CT, 2005 May (Video-tape 4)
- Sister Helen Prejean, Fordham Law, 2005 May (Video-tape 5)
- Journey of Hope; Austin, Texas; Murder Victims Families; Me, 2005 October (Video-tape 6)
- Journey of Hope, Austin, Texas, 2005 October (Video-tape 7)
- Journey of Hope; Austin, Texas; Juan Mendez, 2005 October (Video-tape 8)
- Journey of Hope; National Coalition Awards #1, Austin, Texas, 2005 October (Video-tape 9)
- Journey of Hope; Austin, Texas; No Silence, No Shame, 2005 October (Video-tape 10)
- National Coalition, Austin, Texas; Joe Lenfoe #2, 2005 October (Video-tape 11)
- Execution; Huntsville, Texas, 2005 November (Video-tape 12)
- National Coalition, Austin, Texas #1, 2005 November (Video-tape 13)
- Death Penalty Session; Albany Assembly, 2005 December (Video-tape 14)
- David Kaczynski, Ethical Culture, 2005 (Video-tape 15)
- David Kaczynski, Ethical Culture Exercises; Murder Victim's Family Member, 2005 (Video-tape 16)
- San Quentin Execution; Clarence Ray Allen, 2006 January (Video-tape 17)
- Sister Helen Prejean, NY CLA, 2006 March (Video-tape 18)
- Sister Helen Prejean, St. Joseph's, Patchogue, NY, 2006 March (Video-tape 19)
- North Carolina Execution; Willie Brown, 2006 April 21 (Video-tape 20)
- Criminal Bar; Tavern on the Green, 2006 June (Video-tape 21)
- North Carolina Execution; Samuel Flippen, 2006 August 18 (Video-tape 22)
- Journey of Hope; Church of the Ascension; Virginia Beach, VA, 2006 October (Video-tape 23)
- Journey of Hope; Church of the Redeemer; Mechanicsville, VA; Barbara Allen, 3 Klassen Sisters, 2006 October (Video-tape 24)
- Journey of Hope, Manassas, VA; D.C. Bridge; Helen, Williamsburg, 2006 October (Video-tape 25)
- Journey of Hope, Richmond, VA; St. Edward's, 2006 October (Video-tape 26)
- Audiotaping and Videotaping: My History of Them and Why They are So Special to Me, Undated (Box 1 (Clare Hogenauer Papers ), Folder 1)
- My Athletic and Adventure Sport History, Undated (Box 1 (Clare Hogenauer Papers ), Folder 2)
- Six Degrees of Separation, Undated (Box 1 (Clare Hogenauer Papers ), Folder 3)
- Testimony Against the Death Penalty Before the New Jersey Commission, Undated (Box 1 (Clare Hogenauer Papers ), Folder 4)